

# **VALENTIN LOPEZ**

# CONTACT



valentinlopezandres@gmail.com



valentin--lopez



valenlopez993



https://valentinlopez.netlify.app/

# **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish Native
- English Fluent
- French Fluent

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Python
- Pytorch

MCP

• AWS - Sage Maker

• Nvidia Deepstream

Transformers

- C/C++
- Flutter
- Flask
- PostgreSQL
  Gstreamer
- SQLAlchemy
  Nvidia Jetson
- Git
- Docker
- Linux

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Communication
- Teamworking
- Collaboration
- Leadership
- Curiosity
- Proactivity
- Organization
- Troubleshooting

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a mechatronics engineer with a double degree with focus on computer science and 2 year of experiece working with AI/ML systems.

As a team player, I feel comfortable working with people from different backgrounds and areas of expertise, listening to their ideas and contributing with my owns.

I am really curious, specially on AI, so I spend a lot of time seeking for ways to improve my skills or learn new ones.

I am currently looking for a full-time role in AI, particularly in computer vision.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

### MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER - ANT AUTOMATION | Jul 2024 - Present

Worked on the development of a computer vision system for pallet assembly control in a wholesale distribution center. I was responsible for the entire backend pipeline, including database management, research, model preparation, training, and deployment of computer vision models. The system was integrated into embedded platforms (NVIDIA Jetson devices)

- Machine Learning
- Database management
- Nvidia Jetson

#### Software:

- Deepstream
- Pytorch
- Gstreamer
- Linux

# AI ENGINEER - HOOMANO | Jul 2023 - Dec 2023

Worked as a research intern focused on training and evaluating open-source large language models (LLMs) to contribute to the development of an opensource digital assistant platform that helps companies and individuals build their own Al-powered assets.

#### Skills:

- Large Language Models
- PEFT Methods

#### Software:

- AWS Sage Maker
- Transformers HF

#### NLP PROGRAMMER - CERV | Feb 2022 - Jun 2022 - More info here

Developed an intelligent dialog system for the Pepper robot, enabling it to recognize potential speakers, interpret their intent, and respond with appropriate actions

#### Skills:

- NLP system development
- Speech-To-Text models

#### Software:

- Python Spacy
- ROS

#### **EDUCATION**

### École Nationale d'Ingénieurs de Brest - France

Generalist Engineering | Feb 2022 - Feb 2024

#### Universidad Nacional de Cuyo - Argentina

Mechatronics Engineer | Mar 2018 - Mar 2024